Cristian Felix

cristian.felix@nyu.edu 718 913-9132

New York - United States

Summary

I am a PhD Student at New York University Polytechnic School of Engineering, currently developing projects involving visualizations for text associated to structured data, and TA for the visualization course teaching D3js. Before starting my PhD I worked for 10 years in the area of software development and IT Infrastructure.

Education

New York University - NY, USA PhD Student, Computer Science, 2014 – Present

Universidade Presbiteriana Mackenzie - Sao Paulo, Brazil Bachelor's degree, Information Systems, 2009 – 2012

Research Interests

- Information visualization
- Human Computer Interaction
- Natural Language processing
- Text Mining
- Visual opinion analysis

Research Projects

TextTile – 2016 - An Interactive Visualization Tool for Seamless Exploratory Analysis of Structured Data and Unstructured Text

- Paper to appear at IEEE VAST 2016
- Demo available at: http://nyuvis.github.io/texttile/

WHS Explorer - 2015 - Tool developed to explore documents generated during the United Nations - World Humanitarian Summit consultations.

- Winner of the United Nations #VisualizeChange challenge
- Demo available at: http://nyuvis.github.io/whs/

RevEx -2015 – Faceted search tool developed with Journalists from ProPublica for analysis's of 1.6 Millions reviews from Yelp.

- Knight Foundation Prototype Fund Recipient
- Public version to be released on July, 2016
- <u>Paper</u> published on Computation + Journalism 2015 at Columbia University
- 3 articles produced using the tool: The Economist, Washington Post, NPR
- Demo available at: http://nyuvis.github.io/revex/

Data Mining in Social Networks – 2012 - A study of the relationship between the content of tweets of a user and the content of the tweets of their friends

Face Recognition in JAVA – 2010 – A study of the use of JAVA in the field of face detection and recognition.

Experience

Web developer consultant at Softing Automação (www.softing.com.br) August 2011 - 2014 (3 years)

Responsible for project and develop a Web version of current CRM software. Worked developing and supporting the developing team. The new CRM have been developed using the latest Web technologies like C# 4.0, Razor, MVC, JQuery, KnockoutJS, RequireJS and SignalR.

IT Coordinator at Ação Comunitaria (www.acomunitaria.org.br)

July 2004 – Jul 2014 (10 years)

Responsible for the IT department, including: Project management and software development, infrastructure management and IT user support.

- Developed a software to control 6.000 students each year used through 30 different sites using ASP.Net, C# and SQL Server, today this software is deployed at Windows Azure.

Certifications / Scores / Honors

ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management, Exin August 2012 Mensan, Mensa Brasil, December 2010

Courses

IT Governance - COBIT, Project Management - PMI, Scrum Master

Skills & Expertise

D3js, Information Visualization, HCI, Javascript, Text Mining, SQL, Scrum, HTML, CSS, React, Redux, JAVA, NodeJs, MongoDb,